Guide to the James H. Karales photographs, 1953-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Vietnam Series, 1963-1967, (14 boxes)
  - Vietnam Finished Prints
    - Chaplain, Vietnam, 1965 [Group of troops facing camera, back of chaplain to camera], 1963-1967, 20 x24 inches) (Box 29, Image RL-10017-P-134)
      Legacy identifiers: 2735 11:10A
    - [Group of children standing between barbed wire and cane fence], 1963-1967, 8.5 x 13.5 in (Box 29, Image RL-10017-P-135)
      Legacy identifiers: 1610 40:23; GDC 2773
    - [Sharpened points of cane facing camera, sign with skull and cross bones hangs below], 1963-1967, (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 29, Image RL-10017-P-136)
      Legacy identifiers: 47:12; GDC 2780
- Civil Rights Series, 1965, (5 boxes)
  Series of images taken by Karales during the march for voting rights from Selma to Montgomery, Ala., March 1965, while on assignment for Look magazine. Includes the widely-reproduced photographs of an African American boy enveloped by the U.S. flag, and civil rights marchers with the U.S. flag on the crest of a hill. The following civil rights movement leaders and activists are also depicted: Andrew Young (2309:31, 38, 41, 44), Martin Luther King, Jr. (2309:33, 37, 40, 44), James Baldwin, the author of Selma to Montgomery, Alabama Civil Rights March (2039:44), and Joan Baez (2039:44).
  Series includes thirteen large black-and-white gelatin silver prints ranging in size from 11x14 to 20x24 inches, as well as contact sheets and work prints (5x7 and 8x10 inches), and negatives. Related civil rights movement images are housed in the Martin Luther King Jr. Series and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) Series. All prints are marked on the back with the photographer's roll and frame number.
  - Civil Rights Contact Sheets, (5 folders, 56 prints)
    The contact sheets include Karales' markings indicating images selected for proof prints or finished prints. The job number represented is 2309, all rolls. There do not seem to be duplicate sheets.
    - Contact sheets: Job 2309 (Box 19)
  - Civil Rights Work Prints, (59 folders; 128 prints)
    Contains 57 5x7 and 71 8x10 work prints. Numbers represent rolls and frames, and are marked on the backs of the prints. Folders are titled with the roll numbers housed within. Typically only a few frames were developed from each roll, with the exception of rolls 33-44, for which at least half a dozen frames were printed. Two folders house 14 duplicate prints.
    - Work prints: Job 2309, roll numbers 1-44, with a few gaps in roll numbers (Box 19)
  - Civil Rights Negatives Series, (50 negative folders)
    Approximately 250 negative strips accompanied by a few large-format negatives, representing film rolls 1 through 50 of Job 2309. Negative folders are labeled with roll numbers.
    - Negatives: Job 2309, rolls 1-50 (Box 20)
  - Civil Rights Finished Prints, (8 folders, 13 prints)
    Four black-and-white silver gelatin prints measuring 11x14 inches, eight measuring 16x20 inches, and one 20x24 print. Several prints share similar content. Some are matted. Where possible, the prints are arranged chronologically by the original job, roll and frame numbers. If no roll and frame numbers exist, the prints are arranged by the Gary Davis Collection (GDC) number. Some images bear original titles; titles in brackets have been supplied by library staff.
    - [Men holding three flags], 1965, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-137)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 4:32
    - [Protest poster of one black man and one white man kneeling before Christ], 1965, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-138)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 7:14; GDC 2729
    - [God is Color Blind, Father Forgive], 1965, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-139)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 15:8; GDC 2628
    - Civil Rights on the Selma March, 1965 [Hands clasped in front of religious robes], 1965, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-140)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 17:12A; GDC 2560
      Same content as RL-10017-P145 (16 x 20 inches).
    - [Young man enveloped in U.S. flag], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-141)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 4:19
      Matted.
    - [African American boy atop a white man's shoulders], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-142)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 7:30
    - [Civil Rights marchers along ridge under stormy skies], 1965, (10.75 x 16.5 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-143)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 8: 27
      Same content as print RL-10017-P015 (13 x 19 inches); digital print by Alex Harris; matted.
    - [Civil Rights marchers along ridge under stormy skies], 1965, (13 x 19 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-216)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 8:27
      Same content as print RL-10017-P143 (10.75 x 16.5 inches); digital print by Alex Harris; matted.
    - [A family crowds their porch and stoop, looking into camera], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-144)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 13:22; GDC 2309?
    - Civil Rights on the Selma March, 1965 [Hands clasped in front of religious robes], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-145)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 17:12A; GDC 2309?
      Same content as print RL-10017-P140; mounted.
    - [Priest and man sitting on hood of U.S. Army truck, holding American flag], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-146)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 20:18; GDC 2785
    - [Two photographers, left foreground], 1965, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-147)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 40:24; GDC 2309?
    - [Large group of African Americans standing in front of Blue Flame Drive Inn, waving], 1965, (20 x 24 inches) (Box 29, Image RL-10017-P-148)
      Legacy identifiers: 2309 1:31A
- Lower East Side Series, 1969, 1975, 1985, (6 boxes)
  Series of black-and-white images taken by Karales during three visits roughly ten years apart to New York City's Lower East Side neighborhoods. The images, taken on assignment with Look magazine, feature street scenes and individual portraits of East Side residents, with subjects and settings including families, children, individuals, dogs, murals and graffiti, street games, drug abusers, a community clean-up of derelict building lots, and other social gatherings. The Reverend Bruce Ritter, the founder of the Covenant House homeless youth shelter, is featured in many portraits and scenes. A transcript of a lengthy interview with Father Ritter is also found in the Lower East Side Subseries of the Manuscripts and Printed Materials Series. The images in the collection are not marked with corresponding travel dates; they are arranged in original order as received.
  - Lower East Side Contact Sheets, (15 folders, 172 prints)
    Jobs represented: Job 74, 2175, 5264, and F740. It is not clear which of the jobs pertain to which travel dates.
    - Contact sheets: Job 74, rolls 1-19 (for which there do not appear to be prints); Job 2175, rolls 1-12; Job 5264, rolls 1-67, 74-84; and Job F740, rolls 1-26 (Box 21)
  - Lower East Side Work Prints, (34 folders; 175 prints)
    Contains 2 4x6, 47 5x7, and 126 8x10 work prints. Numbers represent rolls and frames, and are marked on the backs of the prints. Of the 47 5x7 prints, 5 are duplicates; of the 126 5x7 prints, 39 are duplicates. Jobs represented are: 2175, 1075 (for which there are no contact sheets), 5264, and F740. Folders are titled with the roll numbers housed within.
    - Work prints: Job 2175, rolls 1-11; Job 5264, rolls 6-83, with some gaps in numbers; and Job 1075, rolls 10-12; and duplicates (Box 21-22)
  - Lower East Side Negatives, (50 negative folders)
    - Negatives: roll numbers 1-40 and 1A-10A (Box 23)
  - Lower East Side Finished Prints, (22 prints)
    - [Woman stands right foreground in bedroom, pointing, with graffiti on the walls], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-149)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 15:34; GDC 2737
      Same content as print RL-10017-P158 (16 x 20 inches).
    - [Two children stand with fire hydrant spraying water behind], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-150)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 16:7; GDC 2726
    - [Man standing right of frame, black umbrella fills rest of frame], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-151)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 22:2; GDC 2723
    - [Long perspective of street with line of trees and many people], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-152)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 31:15; GDC 2739
    - [Girl holds onto locked chain-link fence], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-153)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 45:20A; GDC 2735
    - [Older woman sits in chair by trunk of a car, woman stands behind], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-154)
      Legacy identifiers: 74 4:32; GDC 2740
    - [Older woman sits in chair by the trunk of a car, two girls sit on stoop in background], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-155)
      Legacy identifiers: 74 4:35; GDC 2736
    - [Four boys play football in street], 1969, 1975, 1985, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-156)
      Legacy identifiers: 74 12:12; GDC 2738
    - [Woman sitting on edge of bed, lifts baby above her head], 1969, 1975, 1985, 14 x 17 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-157)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 17:12; GDC 2788
    - [Woman stands right foreground in bedroom, pointing, with graffiti on the walls], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-158)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 15:34; GDC 2787
      Same content as print RL-10017-P149.
    - August 5th, 1969 [Kids playing in a kiddie pool on sidewalk], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-159)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 19:12
    - August 6th, 1969 [Family leans upon the side of a car, with woman holding baby, another baby sits on trunk], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-160)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 32:13
    - [Kids playing around decrepit building, two girls foreground looking into camera], 1969, 1975, 1985, (13 x 19.5 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-161)
      Legacy identifiers: 5264 46:24
      Same content as RL-10017-P162 (16 x 20 inches); mounted.
    - [Kids playing around decrepit building, two girls foreground looking into camera], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-162)
      Legacy identifiers: 46:24; GDC 2786
      Same content as RL-10017-P161 (13 x 19.5 inches).
    - [Shot through doorway onto street, girl and boy standing in street], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-163)
      Legacy identifiers: 48:5A
    - [Men playing music on street], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-164)
      Legacy identifiers: 51:13
    - [Woman standing with eyes closed, family behind], 1969, 1975, 1985, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P-165)
      Legacy identifiers: 83:17
    - [Two women, one sitting, one leaning], 1956, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-166)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2571
    - [Room full of people, camera focussed center right on woman talking, hand on head], 1956, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-167)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2572
    - [Three people embrace, eyes closed], 1956, (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-168)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2592
    - [Two women sit looking to left frame, man stands on chair behind them], 1956, (7.75 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-169)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2620
    - [Woman, arms akimbo, stands opposite little girl holding a doll], 1956, (8.5 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P-170)
      Legacy identifiers: GDC 2621
- Other Photographic Work Series, (50 prints)
  Consists of smaller bodies of work, comprising solely 50 black-and-white prints, 23 of which are single prints, with the others organized into the following original categories established by Karales: Andrea Doria (1956), California (1957); Diana Vreeland (1965); W. Eugene Smith (undated); Prison (undated); and Speech Therapist (undated). Organized in chronological order by project, then within by Gary Davis Collection identifier. The single prints appear last.
  - Andrea Doria, 1956, (1 folder, 5 prints)
    Five black-and-white gelatin silver prints, ranging in size from 7.75x13.5 to 11x14 inches Captions in brackets supplied by library staff. The images depict families awaiting survivors from the sinking of the transatlantic passenger ship Andrea Doria off the coast of Massachusetts in 1956.
    No job numbers or roll numbers have been identified.
    - [Two women center frame], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P166)
      (GDC 2571)
    - [Room full of people], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P167)
      (GDC 2572)
    - [Three people embracing], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P168)
      (GDC 2592)
    - [Two women sitting, man stands on chair behind them], (7.75 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P169)
      (GDC 2620)
    - [Woman, arms akimbo, stands opposite little girl holding a doll], (8.5 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P170)
      (GDC 2621)
  - California, 1957, (1 folder, 10 images)
    Ten gelatin silver prints ranging in size from 8x13.5 to 11x14 inches, comprising nature and landscape shots taken in Carmel and Death Valley, California. Prints from Death Valley capture cloud formations against dark sky. Several prints share similar content; some prints are undated. Where possible, the prints are arranged chronologically by the original roll and frame numbers. If no roll and frame numbers exist, the prints are arranged by the Gary Davis Collection number. Original captions are retained; captions in brackets have been supplied by library staff.
    - Cloud Symphony, 1957 [Combed clouds behind shadowed mountain range, long distance horizontal shot], (8 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P171)
      (18:6/PF29156/GDC 2732)
    - [Airplane wing in the clouds], (9.5 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P172)
      (GDC 2547)
    - [Airplane wing in the clouds], (9.5 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P173)
      (GDC 2669)
      Copy of RL-10017-P172
    - Cloud Symphony, Death Valley, CA [Sun sets, smoke stack in distance], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P174)
      (GDC 2564)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P175 (9 x 13.5 inches)
    - Cloud Symphony, Death Valley, CA [Sun sets, smoke stack in distance], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P175)
      (GDC 2742/PF29157)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P174 (11 x 14 inches)
      Mounted
    - Cloud Symphony, 1957 [Clouds behind shadowed house], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P176)
      (GDC 2727/PF29522)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P177 (11 x 13.5 inches)
    - Cloud Symphony, 1957 [Clouds behind shadowed house], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P177)
      (GDC 2731/PF29159)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P176
    - Carmel, California, 1957 [Wind-worn tree trunks], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P178)
      (GDC 2728/PF29520)
    - Cloud Symphony, 1957 [Combed clouds behind shadowed mountain range, vertical shot], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P179)
      (GDC 2733/PF29532)
    - Cloud Symphony, 1957 [Clouds behind shadowed mountain range, mid range horizontal shot], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P180)
      (GDC 2734/PF29535)
  - Diana Vreeland, 1965, (1 folder, 3 prints)
    Three gelatin silver prints measuring 9x13.5 inches document noted columnist and fashion editor Diana Vreeland at work and in her office at Vogue. The prints are arranged by the Gary Davis Collection number (listed in parentheses immediately under the caption). A Rubenstein Library identification number has been assigned to each print (to the far right of the caption). Original captions are retained; captions in brackets have been supplied by Rubenstein Library staff.
    - [Vreeland, Marissa Berenson and another woman], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P181)
      (GDC 2614/VF6658)
    - [Vreeland examines drawing with man], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P182)
      (GDC 2665)
    - [Vreeland smoking cigarette in her office at Vogue], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P183)
  - W. Eugene Smith/Juanita Smith, undated, (1 folder, 2 prints)
    Two gelatin silver print portraits of Juanita Smith, daughter of photojournalist W. Eugene Smith, about age 5. The prints measure 9x13.5 inches. Captions in brackets have been supplied by library staff.
    - W. Eugene Smith/Juanita Smith [Child with feet on table, hands clasped behind head], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P184)
      (GDC 2618)
    - W. Eugene Smith/Juanita Smith [Shot from behind, child looking left, holding maple leaves], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P185)
      (GDC 2658)
  - Prison, undated, (1 folder, 3 prints)
    Three gelatin silver prints measuring 9x13.5 inches. Captions in brackets have been supplied by library staff.
    - [Shot through cell bars, man sitting on bed left foreground], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P186)
      (7:27/GDC 2581)
    - Prison, person in jail [Window reflects man in cell, reflecting man shaving in mirror], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P187)
      (GDC 2580)
    - [Clasped hands through white cell bars, perspective down hall of cells], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P188)
      (GDC 2666)
  - Speech Therapist, undated, (1 folder, 4 prints)
    Four gelatin silver prints documenting interactions between a speech therapist and his young charges. Images derive from a 1960 Look profile of Richard Adams, an African American speech therapist and social worker who worked with primarily white children in rural Iowa. The prints are undated; they are arranged by the Gary Davis Collection number. Captions in brackets have been supplied by library staff. All prints measure 9x13.5 inches.
    - [Girl holds bouquet of flowers under therapist's chin], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P189)
      (GDC 2582/FC 42-22-2A)
    - [Girl clasps therapist's thumb], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P190)
      (GDC 2583/FC 42)
    - [Therapist left foreground, awaits train at the station], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P191)
      (GDC 2593)
    - [Girl holds speech therapist's chin in hands], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P192)
      (GDC 2634/FC 42)
  - Single Prints, 1953-1958 and undated, (5 folders, 23 prints)
    Twenty-three gelatin silver prints ranging in size from 7x13.5 to 16x20 inches. Most prints are undated unless otherwise indicated. Several prints share content; some are matted or mounted. The prints are arranged by the Gary Davis Collection number (listed in parentheses immediately under the caption). Original captions have been retained; captions in brackets have been supplied by Rubenstein Library staff.
    Subjects include barns, stilt-walkers, ambulances, and abstract images; places docoumented include Bartlesville, Oklahoma, New Orleans, New York, and Taos, New Mexico.
    - [Abstract; patterns resemble gauzy curtains in front of dripped paint], 1958, (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P193)
      (GDC 2782/PF23249)
    - Barn series, Ohio, 1953, (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P194)
      (GDC 2567)
    - Barn series, Ohio, 1953, (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P195)
      (GDC 2671)
      Copy of RL-10017-P194
    - [Extreme close-up of horse's head and neck], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P196)
      (GDC 2677)
    - [Close-up of leaves of plant with water droplet], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P197)
      (GDC 2650)
    - Ambulance [Looking into windows of ambulance at night], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P198)
      (GDC 2641)
    - Ambulance [Looking into windows of ambulance at night], (7 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P199)
      (GDC 2644)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P198
    - Ambulance [Looking into windows of ambulance at night], (7 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P200)
      (GDC 2722/PF29526)
      Same content as print GDC 2641; copy of RL-10017-P199
    - [Law offices of Pines and Sterling, window graffiti above], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P201)
      (GDC 2570)
      Same content as RL-10017-P202
    - [Law offices of Pines and Sterling, window graffiti above], (7 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P202)
      (GDC 2705)
      Same content as RL-10017-P201
    - [Mostly dark frame, street light illuminates the front of a Volkswagen Beetle], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P203)
      (GDC 2703)
    - New Orleans [Older woman center frame, cigarette wedged in side of mouth, shutters behind], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P204)
      (GDC 2643)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P205
    - New Orleans [Older woman center frame, cigarette wedged in side of mouth, shutters behind], (16 x 20 inches) (Box 28, Image RL-10017-P205)
      (GDC 2779/PF23322)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P204
    - New York [Looming high rises, pigeon flies in right frame], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P206)
      (GDC 2663)
    - Philips 66 Building, Bartlesville, OK, (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P207)
      (GDC 2545)
    - [Reflection of a building on window, inside window hang globular lights], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P208)
      (GDC 2672)
    - Taos, New Mexico, 1957 [Church right frame, pigeons in flight top left frame], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P209)
      (GDC 2662)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P210
    - Taos, New Mexico, 1957 [Church right frame, pigeons in flight top left frame], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P210)
      (GDC 2730)
      Same content as print RL-10017-P209
    - [Man on stilts walks down street], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P211)
      (GDC 2616)
    - [Man on stilts stands on sidewalk, looking at camera], (9 x 13.5 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P212)
      (GDC 2654)
    - [Man on stilts walking down the middle of the street, shot from behind], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P213)
      (GDC 2655)
    - [Toddler sits in shopping cart, lines of shopping carts behind], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P214)
      (GDC 2675)
    - [Tuba fills frame, with man's head peeking out bottom frame], (11 x 14 inches) (Box 26, Image RL-10017-P215)
      (GDC 2579)
- Unidentified Photographic Materials Series, undated, (1 folder)
  - Unidentified contact sheets (Box 22)
    Images are of individuals or groups of individuals, and seem to be shot in corporate settings; two sheets appear to be abstract images of beads.
- Manuscripts and Printed Materials Series, 1955-2002 and undated, bulk 1965-2002, (2 boxes and 5 oversize folders)
  Contains biographical information in the form of curriculum vitae, interviews, and personal essays on teaching and photography; printed materials such as clippings, flyers, programs, magazine layouts, and other publicity relating to exhibits and published works; and a small group of correspondence, chiefly with publishers. Arranged within subseries and in chronological order.
  - Biographical Information Subseries (oversize), 1999
    - McBride, Caryn, "Through the eyes of the witness," Westchester Generations, 1999 Oct. (Box 30)
  - Biographical Information Subseries, 2000-2002 and undated, (6 folders)
    - Interview with James Karales by Sam Stephenson, 2000 Sept. 16 (Box 32)
    - Obituary, The New York Times, 2002 Apr. 5, (2 copies) (Box 32)
    - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box 32)